them a text editor for writing code where you navigate around the screen
它们是用于编写代码的文本编辑器，您可以在其中
with a keyboard instead of a mouse it's based on the original unix text editor
使用键盘而不是鼠标在屏幕上
vi which came about in 1976 then vi improved or vim followed it in 1991 with
a bunch of improvements but why in the age of modern ides would you ever want
导航 在现代 IDE 时代，您是否
to use a keyboard-based text editor when you write code all day every day your
愿意使用基于键盘的文本编辑器？每天整天写代码时，每次触摸鼠标时，您的
fingers should be glued to the keyboard at all times every time you touch the
手指都应该始终粘在键盘上，
mouse your productivity declines learning to code with them is like
您的工作效率会下降学习编码 它们就像
learning to play an instrument it'll be painful at first but that pain will lead
学习演奏乐器一样，一开始会很痛苦，但这种痛苦会导致
to more precise and productive code editing in the future them runs in the
将来更精确和更高效的代码编辑它们在
terminal and it's installed on almost every machine and at some point you'll
终端中运行，并且几乎安装在每台机器上，在某些时候你
likely find yourself accidentally dropped into them with no way to escape
可能会 发现自己不小心掉入其中，无法逃脱
if you find yourself there you can quit them by typing colonqueue that will
如果您发现自己在那里，您可以通过键入冒号退出它们，这将
close an unmodified file or if it has been modified you can use cubebang to
关闭未修改的文件，或者如果它已被修改，您可以 使用 cubebang
throw away your changes or wq to write the changes and then quit now that we're
丢弃您的更改或使用 wq编写更改，然后退出，因为我们已经
out let's use them to open up a file currently we're in normal mode but we
退出了让我们使用它们打开当前处于正常模式的文件，但我们
can toggle between different modes like insert visual and command line depending
可以在不同模式之间切换，例如插入视觉和命令行
on what we're trying to do we can move around the text with the arrow keys or
取决于我们要做什么，我们可以使用箭头键
the letters h j k l if we find a character we want to delete we can hit x
或字母 h j k l 在文本中移动如果我们找到要删除的字符，我们可以按 x
or double d to quickly delete an entire line if that was a mistake hit u to undo
或双 d 快速删除整行，如果这是一个错误 现在点击 u 撤消
it now currently the document is kind of hard to read so let's add line numbers
它当前文档有点难以阅读所以让我们
by running colon set number and now we can navigate to any line with colon
通过运行冒号集号添加行号现在我们可以导航到带有冒号
number now if we want to change some text we need to go into insert mode by
号的任何行如果我们想更改一些我们需要进入插入的文本 模式通过
hitting i and that frees up the keyboard for us to type into the document once
点击 i 并释放键盘让
we're done modifying our code we can hit the escape key to go back to normal mode
我们在完成修改代码后输入文档，我们可以点击退出键返回正常模式，
but now like any good developer we need to copy and paste some code in here from
但现在像任何优秀的开发人员一样，我们需要复制和粘贴一些 这里的代码来自
stack overflow we can paste from the system clipboard by entering plus p into
堆栈溢出，我们 可以通过在 vim 中输入 plus p 来从系统剪贴板粘贴
vim and now that our software is complete we can hit colon w to save it
，现在我们的软件已经完成，我们可以点击冒号 w 保存它，
then run the program directly from bim with colon bang followed by the shell
然后直接从 bim 运行程序，用冒号 bang 后跟
command we want to run congratulations you're no longer a soy dev but a true
我们要运行的 shell 命令，恭喜你 不再是大豆开发人员，而是真正的
software engineer this has been vim in 100 seconds but stay tuned because you
软件工程师，这已经在 100 秒内完成了 vim，但请继续关注，因为您
don't need to ditch vs code to get the benefits of vim that's why i invited a
无需放弃 vs 代码即可获得vim 的好处，这就是为什么我邀请了
true expert and the instructor of the vim for vs code course joe previt to
真正的专家和vim 讲师 vs 代码课程 joe previt
take us beyond 100 seconds of them hello everyone i'm joe and i will be
带我们超过 100 秒大家好，我是 joe，我将成为
your guide as we go beyond 100 seconds to discuss why you should learn vim and
你的向导，因为我们超过 100 秒来讨论为什么你应该学习 vim 以及
how you can leverage it inside your favorite editor vs code first let's talk
如何在你最喜欢的编辑器中利用它 vs 代码 首先让我们
about why you should learn vim vim is an evergreen skill meaning you can learn it
谈谈为什么要学习 vim vim 是一项常青的技能，这意味着您可以学习
once and the knowledge will last with you for the rest of your career it
一次，并且该知识将在您的整个职业生涯中持续使用它
allows you to work faster and more efficiently within your editor here's a
使您可以在编辑器中更快，更有效地工作这里是
side-by-side comparison on the left we have editing with vim on the right we
左侧的并排比较 我们在右侧使用 vim 进行编辑 我们
have editing without vim as you can see bim lets you do more from
在没有 vim 的情况下进行编辑，如您所见，bim 让您可以从键盘上做更多的事情，
the keyboard meaning you get to spend less time editing and more time coding
这意味着您可以花更少的时间编辑和更多的时间编码
now let's talk about how to set up vim with vs code once you're inside vs code
现在让我们谈谈 如何使用 vs 代码设置 vim 一旦你进入 vs 代码
head over to the extension panel and search vim
前往扩展面板并搜索 vim
you should see the first extension called vim and to make sure it's the
你应该看到第一个名为 vim 的扩展并确保它是
right version double check that it's vs code vim.vim and it should have around 2
正确的版本仔细检查它是 vs代码 vim.vim 和 它应该有大约 200
million installations go ahead and install this extension the
万次安装并安装这个扩展
next thing we're going to do is set up key repeat
接下来我们要做的是设置密钥重复
so head over to google and look up vs code vim github you should see the first
所以前往谷歌并查找 vscode vim github 你应该看到第一个
link which is a github repository called vs code vim vim
链接是 github 存储库 调用vs code vim vim
there you're going to scroll down to the installation section
在那里你将向下滚动到安装部分
in here you'll see instructions for how to
在这里你会看到有关如何
enable key repeating this is a handy thing to add especially
启用键重复的说明这是一个方便添加的东西，特别是
when you're new to vim because it'll allow you to hit the key and it will
当你是 vim 的新手时，因为它允许 你打 他键，它会
repeat as in if you were to hit
重复，如果你按
j to move down find your operating system i'm on mac
j 向下移动找到你的操作系统，我在 mac 上
and then run this in your terminal and now for the changes to take effect
，然后在你的终端中运行它，现在为了使更改生效，
you're going to want to restart vs code to verify that it worked go ahead and
你将要重新启动 vs验证它是否工作的代码继续
create a new file and now you should see that your cursor is a little bit wider
创建一个新文件，现在你应该看到你的光标有点宽
go ahead and hit i this will put us in insert mode and then hit return a bunch
继续点击 i 这将使我们进入插入模式，然后点击返回一堆
of times then hit escape
然后点击转义
and now try hitting and holding k and see if your cursor moves up
和 现在尝试按住 k 键，看看你的光标是否向上移动，
if it moves like this pretty smooth then you've enabled key
如果它像这样平滑移动，那么你已经启用了重复键，
repeating if it gets stuck then you may want to try restarting vs code again or
如果它卡住了，那么你可能想再次尝试重新启动 vs 代码或
revisiting the installation instructions great now that we have our editor set up
重新访问安装说明，因为我们很好 设置好我们的编辑器，
i'd like to teach you a few different commands in vim so we'll review some of
我想教你一些 vim 中的不同命令，所以我们将
the ones that jeff mentioned earlier in the video and then we'll also learn a
回顾 jeff 在视频中前面提到的一些命令，然后我们还将学习
few new ones so inside vs code go ahead and create a new file and save it as
一些新命令，所以在 vs code go 中 前进并创建一个新文件并将其保存为
hello.md now what i want you to do is hit i to enter insert mode and hit
hello.md n 我想让你做的是点击 i 进入插入模式并点击
returns we add a few lines for us to work with and then hit escape great so
返回，我们添加了几行供我们使用，然后点击 escape，
the first commands that we're going to talk about are for navigation and they
所以我们要讨论的第一个命令是用于导航，它们
will be h j k and l so right now we're in command mode so if
将 是 h j k 和 l所以现在我们处于命令模式所以如果
we hit k we'll start moving up if we hit j we'll move down
我们点击 k 我们将开始向上移动 如果我们点击j 我们将向下移动
so remember we just learned k for moving up i like to think of it as kicking a
所以记住我们刚刚学会了 k向上移动我喜欢把它想象成踢 一个
soccer ball up i'm kicking upwards on my editor and j for jumping down use
足球向上，我在我的编辑器上向上踢，j 用于跳下使用
whatever mnemonic comes to mind to help you remember those
想到的任何助记符来帮助你
the next we'll talk about are h and l so i'm going to write hello world here
记住接下来我们要讨论的是 h 和 l，所以我要在这里写下 hello world
and you can do the same so again the way that i did that was i for
和 您可以再次执行相同的操作，就像我在
insert mode start typing hello world and then when you're done hit escape and
插入模式下开始输入 hello world 一样，然后当您完成点击转义后，
you'll be back in command mode so the first one we'll talk about is h so if
您将回到命令模式，所以我们要讨论的第一个是 h 因此，如果
you hit h you'll start moving to the left
您按 h，您将开始向左移动，
as in you're moving to the beginning of the line
就像您正在移动到行首一样
also the h in hello world now once we're there if we want to go
，现在在 hello world 中的 h如果我们想
back right we start hitting l and that will move us towards the ellen world so
回到正确的位置，我们就在那里，我们开始击中 l，这将把我们推向艾伦世界，所以
again figure out a mnemonic that's going to help you remember those for me
再次找出一个助记符，它可以帮助你记住那些对我来说
i like to think of h as in i'm going home to the left
我喜欢把 h 想成 i' 我回到左边
and then l you would think that would be
，然后 l你会认为
l for left but it's actually the opposite of that so l for right great so
l 代表左边，但实际上恰恰相反，所以 l 代表右边很棒，所以
now we're feeling comfortable with navigating in vim again we're in command
现在我们再次在 vim 中导航感到很舒服，我们处于命令
mode we're moving up and down with j and k
模式，我们' 用 j 和 k 上下移动，
and left and right with h and l the other thing to to remember is if you
用 h 和 l 左右移动 要记住的另一件事是，如果你
take a look pause for a second look at your keyboard see where the keys are on
看一下，暂停一下，看看你的键盘，看看键盘上的键在哪里，
your keyboard you should see the h to the left of j and k so that also
你应该看到 h在 j 和 k 的左边，这也
helps me remember and then l is to the right of j and k so it'll take
有助于我记住，然后l 在 j 和 k 的右边，所以这需要
some time but once you got those down you'll be able to navigate seamlessly
一些时间，但是一旦你把它们写下来，你就可以
throughout your editor using vim so the other thing i want to point out is you
使用 vim 在整个编辑器中无缝导航 所以我要指出的另一件事是您
still have access to your mouse so you can click to move around
仍然可以使用鼠标，因此您可以单击 t  o 四处走动，
so there's no need to worry about getting stuck in vim i'm sure you've
因此无需担心卡在 vim 中我敢肯定你
heard horror stories people not being able to exit them luckily using them
听说过人们无法幸运地在 vs 代码中使用它们无法退出的恐怖故事
inside of vs code we're really just using the them key bindings so we don't
我们实际上只是使用它们的键绑定所以我们
have to worry we can close a file we can navigate
不用担心我们可以关闭一个可以导航的文件 现在
no need to to fear being stuck in vim now the next thing i want to point out
不用担心卡在 vim 中我要指出的下一件事
is some editing commands so we will talk about i
是一些编辑命令，所以我们将讨论 i
capital i a
大写 ia
and capital a for editing in a line so we're going to go back to our hello
和大写 a 用于编辑 一行，所以我们要回到我们的 hello
world and you'll see right now the cursor is at the end of the line if i
world，你现在会看到光标
hit shift i or capital i it'll move me in insert mode at the beginning so i
在行尾 我
could write a word like i don't know
可以写一个词，就像我不认识
joe and then if i hit escape i'm back in command mode where i can move around
joe 一样，然后如果我点击退出，我会回到命令模式，在那里我可以四处走动，
so you'll notice the one thing that i want to point out
所以你会注意到我想指出
to a tip is a lot of vim users remap their caps lock key to escape so instead
的一件事是很多 的 vim 用户重新映射他们的大写锁定键以转义，因此
of caps lock being caps lock when i hit the
当我按下键时，大写锁定不是大写锁定，
key it actually is escape and so it's a lot more accessible it's closer it's
它实际上是转义 d 所以它更容易访问它更接近它就
right next to my pinky rather than having to reach to the corner of the
在我的小指旁边，而不是必须到达键盘的角落
keyboard and hit escape so that's one thing i'd encourage you to look into
并点击转义所以这是一件事我鼓励你考虑
remapping your caps lock key to escape if you're serious about learning vim so
重新映射你的大写锁定键以逃避如果你 '认真学习vim所以
we just covered capital i we know that lowercase i
我们刚刚介绍了大写i我们知道小写i
is insert mode right so now what i want to talk about is lowercase a the thing
是插入模式所以现在我要谈论的是小写a
that you got to pay attention to here is the cursor
你需要注意的事情是光标
right now it's on top of the exclamation point so if i hit i it'll move to the
现在它在顶部 的感叹号所以如果我点击我它会移动到
left and now if i go back now if i hit a it'll enter into insert mode but after
左边现在如果我现在回去如果我点击a它会进入插入模式但是
the cursor so like this
在光标之后就像
so again uh if we have like a number two here and we want to add to the beginning
这样再次呃如果我们有一个数字 两个在这里，我们想添加到开头
and make it 22 we'll hit i that'll let us enter at the beginning and now if we
并使其成为 22 我们将点击 i 让我们在开头输入，现在如果我们
want to add to the end like say i wanted to add a
想添加到末尾，比如我想添加一个
period 22 so 22 22 then i can use lowercase a so those are very handy when
句点 22 所以 22 22 然后我可以使用小写字母 a 这样在
you're inserting letters or making changes
您插入字母或进行
in a line now the next one that i want to talk about is capital a and so this
更改时非常方便 现在有一行，我要谈论的下一行是大写a，所以
is like appending to the end of the line so you'll enter insert mode at the end
这就像附加到行尾，所以你将在行尾进入插入模式，
of a line so here i am and i want to add more exclamation points at the end of
所以我在这里，我想添加更多 hello world末尾的感叹号
hello world so if i hit shift a it will move the cursor to the end and it will
所以如果我按shift a它会将光标移动到末尾并
enter into insert mode so now that i can enter a few exclamation points now if we
进入插入模式所以现在我可以输入几个感叹号如果我们
go back to the beginning we can do shift i now we're insert mode
回到开头我们可以做 shift i 现在我们
at the beginning of the line so as you can see
在行首插入模式，因此您可以
the i capital i a capital a are very handy for editing in a line
看到 i 大写 i 大写 a 非常方便在一行中进行编辑
great we've talked about navigation we've
我们已经讨论过导航 我们已经
talked about editing and align now the last two that i want to talk
讨论过编辑和对齐现在 我要谈论的最后两个
about are x and r and these are handy for
是 x 和 r，如果我们回到这里，它们对于
making changes while in command mode if we go back up right here and so i want
在命令模式下进行更改很方便，所以我
to get to the beginning of the sentence so i'm going to hit shift i hit escape
想回到句子的开头，所以我要按 shift 我点击了escape，
because i want to be in command mode so you'll see that i have four j's right i
因为我想进入命令模式，所以你会看到我有四个j，我
don't really need all of those so what we're going to do is actually use x to
不知道 ally 需要所有这些，所以我们要做的实际上是使用 x
delete those so x is kind of like x out of character so i'll hit it three times
删除那些，所以 x 有点像 x的字符，所以我会击中它 3 次
one two three and now i have one j which is correct
1 2 3 现在我有一个 j是正确的
so as you can see we're able to make edits without leaving command mode so we
如您所见，我们可以在不离开命令模式的情况下进行编辑所以我们
just talked about x for exiting out characters now let's talk about r
刚刚讨论了 x 用于退出字符现在让我们讨论 r
for replacing characters so i'm going to go to the h here and i want this to be
用于替换字符所以我要在这里转到 h 我想要这个 是
capital so i'll hit r and then shift h which is just a a capital h and now it
大写，所以我会点击 r 然后将 h这只是一个大写 h 现在
will replace it and again i haven't left command mode here let's do this for 22
它将替换它，我还没有离开这里的命令模式让我们为 22 22 执行此操作
22. let's change this to uh 52 22 so we'll hit r and then five
。让我们将其更改为uh 52 22 所以我们 ' 将按 r 然后按 5
and so basically what it does is it replaces the character
，所以基本上它的作用是将
under the cursor with the new character that you type in so we've talked about
光标下的字符替换为您输入的新字符，所以我们已经讨论过
navigation with hjkl we've talked about editing in line with i capital i a and
使用 hjkl 进行导航，我们已经讨论过根据 i 大写 i a 进行编辑 和
capital a and now i've talked about making changes while in command mode
大写a，现在我已经谈到了在x和r的命令模式下进行更改，
with x and r i hope you enjoyed that brief introduction to them inside vs
希望你喜欢t
code if you'd like to learn more head over to vimfovsco.com
如果您想了解更多内容
and check out my course it's got 100 exercises to help you learn how to use
，请访问 vimfovsco.com，查看我的课程
vim inside vs code and we teach you 22 different commands
use the coupon code fireship for five dollars off thanks for watching and i
优惠券代码 fireship 可减五美元 感谢收看，
will see you in the next one
我们下期再见